Praveen Dirishala

Email: dirishala.praveen@gmail.com Mobile: (+91) 9885981389

PROFILE SUMMARY

Highly driven system administrator with 5+ years of experience managing the technical and functional operation and maintenance of assigned systems. Adept in supporting and troubleshooting advanced technical issues within computer hardware, network infrastructure, operating systems and software installations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Oct-2021 to Present Bakhresa SA Pvt Ltd South Africa Computer Network and Systems Engineer.
- Working with Netcom IT Solutions Pvt Ltd from Apr-2019 to Jul-2021 as L1-Desktop Engineer.
 Client location is Tata Projects (Quality Services) Pvt Ltd. Hyderabad.
- Working with Glob tier InfoTech Pvt. Ltd since June-2017 to Mar-2019, as Desktop Engineer. Client location Mahindra and Mahindra Automotive and Farm Equipment Division Zaheerabad

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- Diploma in Dimensions International college 2017.
- Degree specialization B.B.A PRIST Deemed University 2015.
- Sree Narayana Junior College Intermediate -2012
- Triveni Talent School- 10th class-2009

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technical Support
- Knowledge of computers and other hardware devices
- Systems Administration
- User Configuration/Management
- Azure
- Procurement
- Active Directory
- Problem solving
- Communicator
- Hard working
- Packages: Open Office, MS Office, Office o36
- Active Directory, Server All

Work Experience

October 2021 to Present BAKHRESA SA (PTY) LTD South Africa Computer Network and Systems Engineer

Key Result Areas:

• Administered, installed, and configured site hardware and software while troubleshooting any issues.

- Managed and supervised service desk teams for phone, desk side, and remote service desk support.
- Developed and maintained documentation for hardware, systems, and software licensing.
- Took charge as technical lead for coordinating property system installations and upgrades to enhance performance.
- Managed warranties, replacements and upgrades for software.
- Assisted troubleshooting and resolution of Office 365 technical issues.
- Resolved configuration issue related to Microsoft Outlook.
- Collaborated on IT environment planning and budgeting, inclusive of hardware and infrastructure.
- Took ownership of escalated technical and customer services, resolving issues to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Initiated and managed incident management trouble tickets and customer service issues, ensuring prompt resolution to enhance customer satisfaction.
- Developed and implemented Service Desk processes, procedures, and policies.
- Initiated and led Incident Management process for infrastructure and Service Desk issues.
- Performed installation of new machinery and completed repairs for broken equipment, in addition to addressing service call requests.
- Configured VPN settings to enable terminal service, email, file, and print accessibility
- Prepared and sent purchase orders to suppliers, ensuring adequate stock levels.
- Scheduled and expedited supplier deliveries, resolving shortages and addressing missed or late deliveries.
- Approved bills for payment and monitored delivery timings, while overseeing customer and supplier documentation. Explored new supplier opportunities.
- Managed purchase order processing and tracking, while supervising transportation logistics.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

April 2019 to July 2021 with Netcom IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd., India as L1 Desktop Support Engineer.

Key Result Areas:

- Administered, installed, configured and troubles hooted site hardware and software.
- Configured Microsoft Outlook, Windows live mail, Thunderbird & Lotus Notes mail client for Mail Server; Installed VPN technologies (site to site and clients) through firewall Checkpoint & Router; trouble-shooter LAN and WAN components including routers.
- Installed and troubles hooted local printers as well as network printers.
- Created and managed domain controllers, group policy objects, and user accounts & groups.
- Provided support for client operating systems such as Windows Family,
- Configured and resolved Outlook and Teams technical issues.
- Managed video conference calls and addressed related issues.
- Created custom profiles for users to customize desktop settings.
- Solved various computer issues and installed printers and scanners
- Assigned folder permissions to users.
- Provided support to the network team during network outages.

April 2019 to July 2021 with Netcom IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd., India as L1 Desktop Support Engineer.

Key Result Areas:

 Provided efficient desk-side support to internal service users, resolving issues promptly and accurately.

- Delivered exceptional PC support, leveraging extensive expertise in various Windows and Microsoft Office applications.
- Handled support desk calls, effectively communicating complex technical information for optimal service user understanding.
- Managed antivirus installation, scans, monitoring, and security protocols to ensure system privacy.
- Tested connections before scheduled meetings to ensure smooth video conferences.
- Created user profiles and personalized desktop settings.
- Developed and implemented custom user profiles and personalized desktop settings for enhanced user experience.
- Configured audio-visual equipment to enhance performance and functionality.
- Ensured timely installation of AV systems for external events by providing appropriate equipment supplies.
- Installed and trouble-shooter barcode printer and scanner.
- Effectively trained new laptop users.
- Addressed and resolved issue with Outlook.
- Managed printer installations, addressed troubleshooting of printer issues, and resolved network problems.
- Executed knowledge transfer to Service Desk team as the primary liaison.
- Collaborated with network team to troubleshoot and resolve network issues.
- Managed domain controllers, group policy objects and user accounts & groups.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 11th May 1994 | **Languages Known:** English, Telugu & Hindi | **Nationality:** India | **Marital status:** Unmarried | Address: Aakriti Esta Tellapur, Hyderabad502032.